in cycle 7 we no longer have any
instructions to issue so from now on we
will not be issuing things let's see
what can we dispatch well we have an
instruction here that is ready and we
have an instruction here they are going
to different units so they can actually
both dispatch in the same cycle so now
both of these instructions have been
dispatched and we will broadcast a
result but there is nothing executing
currently so so we don't broadcast
anything so we will Mark that the
subtract here which is this instruction
has started executing in Cycle s it's
going to become eligible for because
adds and subtracts take two cycles so in
seven and eight this is going to execute
it's going to try to broadcast in cycle
9 the multiplication here which is this
instruction also starts executing in
cycle 7 it's going to take 10 Cycles so
in cycle 17 it's going to try to
broadcast the result the other
instructions are going to wait for these
two so basic
what that means is that nothing is
really going to happen now until the
cycle in which one of these two tries to
broadcast anything because the this
patches are not going to happen because
there is nothing that can go issue
cannot happen because we are done
issuing everything so we can now kind of
fast forward I mean in cycle eight
pretty much nothing happens except that
these two are executing in cycle 9
what's going to happen is this
instruction is going to try to broadcast
and because there is nothing else that
wants to broadcast in this cycle this
broadcast will happen so what's now
going to happen is this subtract is
going to find the register that matches
its tag which is f8 write the value to
f8 and the value is going to be - 2.5 -
7.1 so it's going to be -
9.6 we're going to unram f8 so that it
now forces future instructions to read
from f8 we're going to find instructions
that are waiting for add one like here
and put minus 9
9.6 instead of the tag and then we're
going to free this reservation station
okay and the the subtract has been
writing the result in nine